[dramatic music]
[dramatic music heightens]
[tranquil music]
[singing] She sells seashells
by the sea shore.
The shells she sells
are seashells I'm sure.
-Lil?
Lily?
[sighs]
Lily!
-Zinnia?
What's going on?
-I looked and looked...
[dramatic music]
[dramatic music heightens]
The flashlight died on me.
I can't see anything
out there.
-How could we think that leaving
them alone was okay?
-Lily's out there.
-What kind of parents are we?
-Important thing is that we...
I'm going back out.
[dramatic music]
-Lily!
-Can anyone help us?
-Honey, I know this is really
hard to understand.
But until help arrives...
We're the ones who have
to find Lily.
It's only us.
We're not gonna stop
until we find her.
Lily!
-Lily!
-Slow down Zinnia.
-Up, up, up, up, up!
-Lily!
-Lily.
-Oh, Lily.
Where were you?
Oh...
Where'd you go?
Where'd you go, huh?
Where'd you go Lily bear?
-I was looking for seashells
for you
and there was this nice woman.
She taught me a song.
Why are you crying?
I was coming right back.
[static over baby monitor]
Stop crying.
Where do you come from?
[static continues]
This is my...
-Please get out of my house!
-Hello?
[piano keys played]
-Sweetie. That one's broken.
-[child fussing]
It's like he knows words.
He just won't use them.
-Kids'll grow how they grow,
you can't rush 'em.
-Was I like Jared
when I was little?
-What do you remember about
our summer on the road?
-The summer that lasted years.
-[laughs]
Not Dad's stories, Lil.
Something that's just yours.
-I remember how the wind felt.
Before it was music.
When did it start?
-You went missing, Lil.
Mom and Dad never
said it was my fault.
Not out loud.
But it was all cause of me.
The more nobody talked about it,
The more it was like it never
happened at all.
-Got it?
-Got it.
Yup.
Except... the way you came back.
Like... wherever you went.
Whatever gave you that music...
It's got you too.
-Home is real far.
We're going to get lost
if we don't go back!
Right now!
-Showing me things.
-I have to say
most of us forgot
that this property
even existed.
-That's our Nancy Drews for ya.
-[laughter]
Lily, the little one, she said
this place sounded like home.
-Hmm. Um, so...
Oh, hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Boxes!
-[laughs]
-It didn't matter how much
everything else changed...
when we went to real school,
and mom stopped calling us
her gumboot girls.
[knocking]
All those nights of good night
knocks on the wall.
[knocks]
Just us.
Your music...
That song you played
over and over.
Like it's hypnotized you.
You're always drifting.
Between our world...
and someplace else.
-I'll be right with you, 'kay?
Come on.
I'll be right back.
Even when you surprised us
and got pregnant with Jared.
[baby crying]
-Wrap his arms around him.
-I hear that other place in him.
I'm scared, Zinni.
I think it's calling us home.
Where did I go?
You were at
this little island
that you could walk
to at low tide.
But the thing is
when we found you,
you thought you had only
disappeared for a few minutes.
But you'd been gone for days.
Dad said that a different Lily
came back that day.
It's like you'd been touched
by this frost
that kept you from blooming
while the rest of the world
grew up.
-I don't want the frost
to touch Jared too.
Mom will find out
who's calling us.
[indistinct conversations]
♪
[ominous music]
[water trickling sounds]
-[trees rustling]
-[branches creaking]
-Lily.
[voice echoing]
Lily...
Lily.
You made it.
Oh.
It's not the right time.
-You're hurt.
-You have to promise you won't
tell Jared you saw me.
-How do you know about
my boy?
-You just can't say a word
about me.
Promise.
-But I don't even know
who you are.
-It'll all make sense soon.
Don't be scared.
-Hey!
Come back!
Where'd you go?
[gasps]
Hey! Hey!
Over here! Hey!
[dramatic music intensifies]
-So what's your name?
-I'm Lily.
-Lily. Pleasure to meet you.
My name's Cam.
Man, I can't believe
I found you out here.
Lotta boats don't come
around here for days.
You know you remind me
of a story
that my pappy used
to tell me.
A story about the raven.
How the raven went
to the spirit land
of the salmon people.
And when he was over there
he stole the chief's daughter.
[laughs]
And he brought her over here
and said,
"I'll return you if you promise
"to bring the salmon here
every year."
And you know what?
Every year... the salmon
are here.
It's like my secret spot.
The trees dance with the wind.
Saying, "welcome to the place
of the spirits."
And I show my friends the
monsters I catch... [laughs]
They always wonder
where do you go
and I say, "I go where
the spirits go." [laughs]
Oh, look at that.
Sun break coming up ahead.
Hey Lily. I could take you home
if you wait a few minutes.
-No, I...
I... I'm not from here.
Thank you.
-How are you gonna get home?
-I can take the bus.
-[laughs] Well I think you're
gonna be waiting a long time.
Alright. Well, safe travels.
-Bye Cam.
-You know where to find me.
-Thank you.
[indistinct conversations]
[dramatic music]
[indistinct conversation]
[ominous music]
[truck engine sputtering]
[ominous music intensifies]
[door lock jiggles]
Hello?
[knocking]
[car horn honks]
-Hi.
Uh... can I help you?
-I'm locked out, there's
something wrong with my keys.
-Well... this is 1226.
-Are Bruce and Patty home?
-Bruce doesn't... he doesn't
live here anymore.
-Bruce and Patty
are my parents.
-I'm sorry. I really am.
Inside, Rowan. Soccer's in 20.
-I live here.
My kid's room
is right up there.
-Are you lost?
-Inside means inside.
[dramatic music]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[fighting grunts]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[indistinct conversations]
♪
-Hey Joe.
-Yo.
Oh hey.
What can I get started for you?
-Do you have, like, um...
like, a phone I could borrow
for... just for a minute?
-Yes, I do.
You can take all the minutes
you need.
-Thank you.
Okay.
[dialing]
[line ringing]
-[operator] We're sorry.
You have reached a number
that is no longer in service.
[dialing]
[line ringing]
-[clerk] McKittrick Hotel,
good morning.
Good morning.
Hello?
-No luck, huh?
-Can I borrow your phone book?
-Uh, phone book.
Jeez, uh...
-It's been all online
the last few years.
-Is there someone
you're trying to find?
It's a small city,
maybe I know 'em.
-Bruce and Patty Davies.
-Bruce...
No, I'm sorry. I don't.
You all done with this?
-Thanks.
-Yeah, you bet.
-Hey!
It's not my business but Bruce
may not wanna be found.
-Do you know where he is?
-Not for a long time.
Last I heard he moved into
the seniors home by the mall.
If he's moved on, someone there
might no where.
-Thanks, mister.
Hi. Excuse me.
Uh, I'm looking for my dad,
Bruce Davies.
Do any of you know if...
if Bruce Davies lives here?
[Lily humming]
-[weakly] Lily?
Lil. Lily.
-Dad? Okay, do you want your-
Okay, I'm gonna get your air.
-Dad.
-Lily.
-Zinni.
Wait!
-No.
-It's me.
-We're not doing this again.
-[teary] I closed my eyes and
now nothing is like I remember.
It's like the worst dream
except I pinch myself like Mom
taught us and I don't wake up.
I found the island that you told
me about, Zinni.
The one that I disappeared
when we were kids.
The days passed for you
but not for me.
I think it happened again
but this time it was years...
because it was just the other
night that I left.
[sobbing] It was just
the other night.
[sobbing]
-You put down your ice cream
before the photo
and a seagull ate it.
Jared smiled.
Where's my boy, Zinni?
-I'll dig out her trunk.
-Last time you said you...
-Last time it wasn't Lily.
-You're not the first Lily
to come back.
-Is Jared grown now too?
Why won't you tell me
where my boy is?
-He's nobody's boy anymore.
-I wanna see him.
-That's enough history
for one day.
-Where's Mom?
-I'm gonna go wait in the car.
-Well, hold on.
At least let me call it.
-Zinni... where's Mom?
-My mom's dead.
Wait here.
-Come on. Come on.
-I mean, if it is true,
which, it can't be...
shouldn't we be
telling them?
-Who? The police?
The news?
What, and be the town
punchline again?
-I don't want that woman
sleeping in the same house
as our child.
-It's not our decision.
Look, I booked off work tonight,
Dad's staying over too.
-You know you're being conned...
again.
-You're welcome to stay
somewhere else.
-You believe her.
Zin, your sister is dead.
-What if she's not?
-Zinni?
Where's my boy?
Did something bad happen to him?
-Get in.
Hmph.
You can't breathe a word about
Jared outside this car. 'Kay?
Jared didn't start talking
'till real late.
But when he did he would call
Mom, Mom and Dad, Dad.
And we didn't correct him
so it kinda became true.
He was the loneliest little boy
you ever saw.
[crying] He had these...
sorry...
Um...
He had these imaginary visitors
except they were real to him.
Like another layer over top
of reality, one only he saw.
-Who were they?
-He said they were
from other times
but living in the same place
as us.
Some of them were horrible.
This one he called
the hanging man.
He thought someone had killed
themself in the house.
And we tried everything...
until he started taking things
that he didn't get
from any doctor.
And then we didn't hear so much
about the visitors anymore
'cause the rest of his troubles
swallowed him.
We kept wondering
when we lost him...
but I don't think he
was ever ours to start.
-Can I see him?
-Just...
One thing at a time.
We should get back.
[dramatic music]
-Zinnia's dad gave up years
of his life to look for Lily.
Don't let him down.
[knocking on wall]
[sobbing]
[wind howling]
[eerie music]
[plays piano keys slowly]
[hollow sound]
[creaking]
[plays piano keys slowly]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[continues to play keys slowly]
[thud]
-Zinni?
Ollie?
Hello?
[dramatic music intensifies]
-He lives in there?
-It's real hard to understand,
Lil.
We don't have to.
[dramatic music]
[buzzer ringing]
Jared?
Jared, it's Zinnia.
Your sister Lily...
she's come home.
She wants to see you.
Jared?
[door buzzes]
-You're not coming?
-I can't.
Be careful what you say
to him.
[knocking on door]
[door squeaks open]
Hello?
Can I come in?
Jared?
Hello?
Hi.
-Where's Zinnia?
-Zinnia couldn't stay.
-Who are you?
-I'm Lily.
-Lily's dead.
-I just had to go away
for a while.
-You a ghost?
-Zinnia said...
-Zinnia lies.
-She said that people
from a long time ago
come and visit you.
-I'm better now.
-The same people come
and visit me too.
-No they don't.
-I only see them sometimes.
I can't tell anyone else
but I'm scared.
-You lie too.
-You and me...
It's 'cause we're family.
-No, I don't have
a family anymore.
-I'm your family.
Help me understand...
Please.
-No one ever goes away.
Not really.
Everyone who's ever been
in this room is still here.
Echoing.
And echoing.
-Who's here with us now, Jared?
-They don't visit me anymore.
-I think they do.
-Who are you?
Lily died a long time ago.
You're young.
You're not Lily.
Are you one of them?!
Are you from long ago?!
-I don't know.
No...
You... I saw you.
-I knew it!
Why did you come here?
-I'm sorry, I thought that I...
-You're fucking with me.
-[crying] I didn't mean
to scare you, Jared.
-Don't fuck with me!
-No.
-I don't see you.
Get out!
Get the fuck out!
-Are you okay on your
own tonight?
Work is short staffed
but Ollie's not home,
he's working nights at the dock.
And Rowan's with his grandma
for a few nights.
You're home.
Give it some time
to feel like it.
-That man stole my boy.
-Yeah.
Yeah, I suppose he did.
[furniture moving]
-Zinni?
Ollie?
Who's in there?
[dramatic music]
-Get out of my house!
[dramatic music intensifies]
[knocking]
-Well, we have to find
the original plans,
but it seems pretty solid
to me.
-Too bad, would've made a great
future ex-husband hobble.
-What happened to mom?
-A lot changed real quick
after you left.
-Zinni...
Lil...
You know when you think
back real far,
that sometimes you know how
your mind fills things in?
Things that didn't happen
quite how we thought.
Well the longer
you were missing,
the more you became
something beautiful that me...
and Zinni and your mom
all dreamed together.
Alive in us but that the world
couldn't touch anymore.
How am I doing?
The shadow from that dream,
it got too long for your mom.
Too long and too dark.
And her heart broke in a way
that no time could fix.
You understand?
He was our way of keeping
you close.
Lord, we got all kinda shadows
following us now.
Look, Sarah said she'd see her
without paperwork,
we're booked in tomorrow.
-Shouldn't we start
with a shrink?
-Just give me
'till the weekend
to figure something out
longer term.
-Don't you have extra beds
at work?
-I can't just book my sister
into the hospice.
[phone ringing]
Is that the phone?
-No, you're not...
you're not listening.
You have to stop calling here.
She doesn't have a phone.
We don't know anything
about her. Okay?
It doesn't matter what I think.
I'm not putting her on.
No, no... you don't get
to tell me what to do.
No one wants to talk to you.
-Was that him?
-Did Zinnia take you
to see him?
[phone ringing]
If you encourage his delusions
it will end badly.
[phone ringing]
-Zinnia told me.
-Did she tell you how?
[phone continues to ring]
-Jared?
-You can prove it.
-Prove what?
-Come to the bay ferry at 9:00.
Bring money for it.
-What am I proving?
-But get there right at 9:00
You'll miss it if you're late.
-I'll be there.
-Right at 9:00.
-But what am I proving?
[ferry horn honking]
-[announcement] Welcome aboard.
This is a safety announcement.
Ship personnel are certified to
deal with emergency situations.
Please follow directions
from our officers...
This ship is equipped
with emergency rafts
and life jackets.
For your safety...
-This way.
We're safe on the water.
They can only be here
if they followed us.
You left this.
-Why doesn't anyone talk
to you anymore?
If you see...
then they'll know I'm not crazy.
-Where are we going, Jared?
[Lily humming]
-You hear it too?
I knew it was real.
[indistinct conversations]
-Who are they?
-When are they?
Come on.
[steam whistle blowing]
It's now to them...
same as to us.
Same as always.
There isn't any other time.
People live their whole lives
not knowing the past
is all around them.
He's the one that's been
hunting me.
-Maybe he hears it too.
[intense music]
[grunting]
[heavy breathing]
This way.
-What was that?
-We make time into a straight
line but it's...
it's coming back again
and again.
There's no way out.
[ship's horn honking]
He's been trying to follow me.
-I saw him stab a man.
-On the boardwalk.
Yeah, a long time ago.
He... he wants
to kill me too.
-Why can't we see anyone else?
-Mom was the only one
who believed me.
She hoped that I could
see you.
I never could.
Now I've never been able
to see her.
-Who's the hanging man?
[ship's horn honking]
Zinnia told me.
Who is he?
[door creaking]
[nervous breathing]
-Your heart's galloping.
-Sorry.
-I'll let you in
on a little secret.
Even doctors don't like going
to the doctor.
-It's like it's ticking.
-Mmhmm.
Zinnia did mention to do
some blood tests.
[voice muffled]
[heart beating]
Is there anything
you're going through
that might be causing
her concern?
Would you like me to ask her
to join us?
-[nervous breathing]
-Who's that you was talking to?
-Hello?
-Who were you talking to?
-The doctor.
-It's okay to see things.
Sometimes I see things too.
Have you seen the man
with the black tattoos?
Mom says he isn't real.
But I know he is.
Soon I'll be big enough
to fight back.
Mom says fighting in the war
turned Dad mean...
but I wish he never came home.
-Who's the man with
the black tattoos?
-All along his arms
like spiderwebs.
He's the real scary one,
not Dad.
'Cause he's a ghost.
You're real pretty.
How old are you?
-Hey.
Hey. What's got you spooked,
boo?
-Wanna see under my eye?
-You can tell me anything.
Time won't take that away.
-[screams]
[buzzer]
[knocking]
[squeals]
It's me, Jared.
It's Lily.
-Get in.
[grunting]
Didn't you see him?!
He followed me home last night!
-I saw him as a boy.
He's scared of ghosts,
same as us.
He's scared of you.
-I'm not a ghost.
What are you doing?
-No one's hunting you, Jared.
-[screams]
I need to go to the bathroom.
I... I didn't know you
were coming.
I would've gone first,
if I knew.
-Okay.
[door shuts]
[suspenseful music]
[door opens]
-It's not finished.
-Who is he?
-I found him when I was a kid.
Hidden.
I never showed anyone,
never looked again.
But growing up I...
I saw him more and more.
-The man from last night?
-You're bleeding.
Are you okay?
Want me to tell you a story?
It's about a place.
Once there was an island
where days didn't exist.
No one got older,
no one died.
This island, it had a call,
heard by everyone who visited.
No matter when they went.
Before or after, didn't matter.
The call sounded like home.
It was home.
-It's not real.
-It was.
It is.
And if you follow the sunset
to where the land runs out...
you can find it too.
The wind will show you the way.
To the rock path at low tide.
The seven steps to the moss
and the pollen
and the tree out of time.
I've been there before.
And if you ask the island,
I'm there now.
There you can be alive
in all times.
He hasn't been there
for a long time, Jared.
-Was that the trip then that...
that Jared won
with the scratchy?
-We won. I chose,
he scratched.
-He who scratcheth thy ticket
doth winneth thy pot.
I just remember that whole visit
he was sitting on my lap
and telling all these stories.
And I'd never seen him
talk before
and this time he was
out of breath,
he had so much to say.
All kid stuff.
But ask Zinni,
that trip he was as happy
as a hound with two tails.
Being out of Rupert
was a good thing.
This place has a way
of getting in his mind...
which can be a hard thing
to stop sometimes.
-He was living with us
and holding down a job.
A good one.
You gotta understand how
my son used to worship Jared.
He was his uncle,
best friend, his hero.
And Jared would tell him
about his visitors.
It became their big secret.
And Rowan, he convinced Jared
that he saw them too.
That they were mean
to him too.
And Jared felt so bad
for bringing them into
Rowan's life that...
He wasn't using then.
'Till the day that he thought
that if he killed himself...
the visitors would stop coming.
So he made Rowan look out so
no one would come to the shed.
But when Rowan got a bad feeling
and came back...
he found Jared.
Rowan has these nightmares
where Jared's dead and he wants
revenge for killing him.
We had to take him
to the hospital
to prove that Jared was
still alive.
-If you think you know
what Jared's going through...
We couldn't reach him.
Maybe you can.
[ominous music]
[thudding]
[floorboards creaking]
[nervous breathing]
-Get out of my head.
Get out of my head!
[fighting grunts]
[tapping sounds]
[knocking on window]
-[crying] He broke into my...
that bastard from
the other night.
He broke in.
He came to my house
and he rushed me and he...
tried to kill me!
He's trying to kill me, Lily!
-Slow down.
-[crying] He's not gonna stop.
He's not gonna stop.
-It's okay.
-I...
I had nowhere else to go.
-You're bleeding.
Come inside.
Ollie's not home,
it's just us.
It's 'cause it's haunted.
-If there's somewhere
I can go...
that no one's ever been.
I can't see anyone if I'm the
first one in all time. Right?
-We're not meant to live alone.
-Maybe I am.
Are you my real mom?
I guess I had a feeling.
[crying] I don't wanna
see them anymore.
[crying]
They weren't supposed
to touch it.
Zinnia said it was yours.
-It makes the noise quieter.
All the music in your head.
[piano playing]
♪
-That... that island...
Is it real?
-It feels like home.
[playing piano beautifully]
♪
-My song.
-No! No!
[glass breaking]
Get out!
-No, no, no.
I've been looking for that
little bastard all morning
and now my truck is missing?
Well if she hadn't started
pumping up his fantasies
we'd know where he was and
we wouldn't be here right now.
It's not like this is
the first time, is it?
I swear to God,
if he pawns my truck for more
juice for his arm,
I will strangle that kid.
Forget it. Forget it,
I'll call you from the road.
I'm taking your car!
-What? Hey.
Wait a minute!
Ollie's truck is missing.
It's okay, he's all bark
and no bite.
Hey.
[dramatic music]
-The microfilm reader,
such a beastly thing to move,
so it makes us come to it.
It's library staff only
downstairs but today...
you can be one of us.
-I'd like to see 1920.
-A lot can happen in a year.
Even one that far back.
The microfilms only go back
to the '30s
but our Rupert is a lot
older than that.
Yes, she is.
None of the older stuff
ever got scanned.
But I would start here.
Now...
we close at 3:00 but...
well, you're staff now so take
all the time you need.
-Thank you.
-Be gentle.
You're the keeper
of secrets now.
[mysterious music]
Find anything interesting?
-Oh...
-Sorry dear, I didn't mean
to startle you.
The library's closing.
But don't rush yourself.
I'll be puttering about
a while longer.
-Wait.
Have you ever heard of
a woman named Mary Rose?
She went missing in 1920.
-I haven't heard that name
out loud in a very long time.
-Did they ever find her?
-I don't believe so, Lily.
No.
I don't believe they ever did.
[playing piano keys]
[playing piano beautifully]
♪
[suspenseful music]
-Mary Rose?
It's just us.
I know about the island...
from the painting.
-You're not gonna hurt me?
-Of course not.
I'm Lily.
-What about the angry man?
And the baby?
-That's my boy.
He's just scared.
He knows our island too.
-Not yet.
I wanna go back.
But I can't remember the way.
-You have to follow
the music.
-I try.
But... now it only leads me
to you.
-It led me to you too.
A long time ago.
-Makes time into a dream.
-Do you know what it means?
-I can show you...
if you promise not
to tell anyone.
No one can find me here.
Only you.
-Who is he?
-The island says
it likes visitors.
-Where do they go?
-The island takes them all back.
The island keeps
all its secrets.
-What's in there?
Mary Rose?
[dramatic music]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[chilling music]
[gasps]
[sobbing]
[phone keypad beeping]
Zinnie!
Zin!
-Incredible.
It's incredible.
It's under our feet all along.
No one's in here, Lil.
I wish you'd tell me
what you saw.
-I found him
when I was a kid.
Hidden.
Never showed anyone,
never looked again.
But growing up I saw him
more and more.
-It's not the right time.
He just wanted to find home.
I told him the way.
-What if it's just a painting,
Lil?
♪
[laughing]
Okay. Well...
I think that's it
for now, Dad.
We got a lotta miles
ahead of us today.
-You're one of life's great
mysteries, little bear.
-Do you think the world's
a scary place, Dad?
-I think it can be...
damn terrifying.
But with the right people
around you...
it's beautiful too.
♪
-We'll all be okay.
You'll see.
When it's the end.
-It's a little tough to see,
Lil.
-That's because it's not
the end.
[Lily humming]
Hi.
-Hi.
-What's your name?
-Lily.
-[laughs]
Lily's my name too.
Can I teach you a song?
-Mmhmm.
[humming]
[laughing]